friends I have to make a quick little
video um because somebody asked the
question how can can they basically
they're asking to make a USB stick
persistent so that they can use their
work
laptop to do personal
things and for at least probably half of
you a whole bunch of alarm Bells just
went off and I'm going to set the alarm
Bells off and the rest of you okay now
it's up to you to make the decision and
please if the person here right now and
I am not ripping on them okay I am not
ripping on you at all right I am not
accusing you of anything I am not
telling you you're a bad person I'm not
even saying you're naive I'm saying that
most people don't understand what it
means to use a work laptop and a
personal laptop or a personal computer
and I want to be very clear about this
because it is such a big deal it could
actually change your entire life in
it was the focus of a Silicon Valley
episode I think it was season 3 where um
the main character logs in and Taps on
his computer to change a few letters in
some of their code that was a part of
his personal you know startup effort and
ultimately that was detected and in a
court of law it was the the IP for his
entire company his entire um In-N-Out
algorithm his compression algorithm was
given given to the company that for uh
you know that that only computer the
laptop that he used to just dial in and
and do or to ssh in and he said dial in
what era is it and and type type in
those few little letters and yeah that's
fiction but it's very much up to you to
determine what you think that you're
going because if you get caught there's
extreme legal precedent that any action
even touching a that includes l in with
SSH sshing from your machine into your
own personal machine and doing personal
work over there right and you might
think that they can't know that you're
doing that but they can see your network
outbound connections from the machine
they could put it they're perfectly
within their rights to put a key scanner
on that machine they could even activate
your camera in fact I put tape over mine
that is all their legal right they can
do any of that because it's their
property and if you think that you're
going to be able to stick a VM on there
and run all that stuff and hide it in an
encrypted VM and they I mean they put a
key logger you're screwed right it you
if they there's a million ways that a
company can monitor you and spy on you
if you don't want to be caught doing
things that are personal um whether it's
just writing a blog or a zcas in or
updating your skill stack io. website so
bottom
line um I just want to be sure that
everybody
knows uh that if you if you're doing
that you're taking a risk right and it's
up to you to decide how big that risk is
for me I'm comfortable sshing into my
personal machine from my work machine in
order to look stuff up on on my zle
casting or in you know occasionally to
update my blog or to update skill stack.
IO now I personally am okay with that
and I'm pretty much openly admitting
that I do that and my peers do the same
and they've shared that with me they
regularly will log into another system
and they will do step on that other
system and then they'll exit sometimes
they'll even have uh two separate
windows open at the same time or they'll
have a t-u pain and then another t-u
pain and that's all well and good but
just be careful my friends because as
soon as you copy code from that you
wrote for
work especially if you're a software
engineer if you're an operations person
you might be able to fly under the radar
for a while but if you're a software
engineer forget it and I know this
because I asked when I was at IBM so if
you if you're a software engineer you're
if you literally copy and paste code
from one terminal into another terminal
and that terminal is logged on to
another system outside of the Enterprise
that's a firable offense and you might
not think there's anything about that
but I encourage you to go look at what
ended up causing Google to lose a
lawsuit against Oracle about Java go
look it up it's pretty damn disturbing
but there was a guy who was working on
the jobba team at one point and he
copied all it was was a couple of lines
and because of that Oracle was able to
win a lawsuit against go Google and they
eventually had to make it all the way up
the chain it was a big deal it ran it
was a lawsuit around over 10 years and
it was Oracle saying that that Google
could never have possibly implemented
their own Java virtual machine in the
time that they did and that they surely
must have have have um have hacked it or
something if you if you get into this
kind of legal precedent stuff just I
mean there's a bunch of other rabbit
holes and videos we should make about
this including why you need to be
careful not to taint
yourself if you look at the wrong
proprietary code you could possibly
limit your job opportunities elsewhere
because now you have seen proprietary
code and there are are very strong
penalties for even non-disclosure or
not NDA or
not does not matter non-compete or not
which are illegal in America now thank
God but all of that stuff doesn't matter
if you have looked at proprietary code
and you need to work for another company
who's going to make a product that uses
some similar proprietary code you're in
a scary legal place and that's a
separate video um I don't quite know
where to categorize those kind of videos
those are related to managing your
career as a as a technologist and you
need to be careful with that stuff so so
just you know my my advice to you is to
use one computer for work and to use
another computer for your other stuff
and just buy like a $100 laptop and use
that to log in and if you you know if be
careful I you can't take your personal
laptop to your corporate Network on site
and then use it there if you're using
their
Network they still own
it so I mean I I don't want to be the
one that's that's going to be you know
in that kind of fight um so anyway uh
some people feel the same way about
their phones by the way so I work with
someone who will not do anything work
rated from their phone their phone is
their business um I've chosen to take a
different position and our company has
the mixture of phones where they'll put
you know there's there's a you push a
button and everything it turns into work
mode and then it's out of work mode
right and then you're putting an immense
amount of trust in your corporation if
you're going to do that on your own
private phone but you know it is it is
something to consider uh for me this is
one of the areas where convenience
trumps the rest because I was actually
bike packing a lot and having access to
my notifications and my calendar and all
of that stuff on my phone uh through the
cloud or through whatever was more
valuable to me than having a real solid
separation but I I know people uh
including somebody I work with right now
who maintains a separate phone just for
work and that phone they they put all
that stuff on that phone and then their
other phone is for is for own the
private use and they're carrying two
phones this reminds me of the 90s when
we used to have like you know like five
pagers on our
belts for different things different
departments can we just never talk about
that again all right that's all